Updated June 12th, 2022

Päärni, Risto Anton

## Helsinki, Finland

# **Summary**

My name is Risto Anton Päärni, M.Sc./B.Sc. engineer focusing on AWS project Lifetime Digital Workspace for Intelligent Industries (dws), an InvestEU approved, EBAN funded project at the moment.

I was chosen to participate in Smart Factory/ Industrial internet/ MES /6G Cloud M.S. Program in Metropolia Applied Science 2022-2024, so I am looking for a company to work with and to deliver a Research & Development to customer projects. My Research areas are edge and cloud and its security, and building sustainable ESG Smart Factory solutions and applications and managing its fleet..

As a professional, I offer three hats to your team, namely agile Scrum Project Manager, Cloud Solutions Architect, and thirdly Cloud Developer (C++/C#, JS, Python, GitHub, Docker, GitHub Actions, CI, CD).

As CEO of Lifetime Group my backlog of duties include agile coaching, business development, innovations and brand management, operations of the company, sales, HR, marketing, management accounting.

Risto Anton has public cloud experience for more than 10+ years. He is an experienced solutions architect with deep knowledge of customer business cases on apps services on AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Engine, and with technologies like Kubernetes (k8s) fleet and app services.

Risto Anton has expertise in data architecture design, cloud native based services design and business model based service modeling, APIs, multi-cloud integration solutions and NoSQL / SQL databases. As security practitioner he is the Administrator of Lifetime Group 5 domains solving and managing their hands-on daily security and growth and CX issues.



### **Education**

- Program älykäs teollisuus ko, YAMK, Metropolia, 2022-2024.
- Master of Industrial Management, DI, Technology Entrepreneurship, LUT,2005-2007.
- Bachelor of Software Engineering, insinööri,1991.
   Metropolia, 1991. ICT Project Manager datanomi, Amiedu, 2017-2018.
- JYET, Leadership Program, BusinessCollege, 2019-2020.
- Matriculation examination, Myyrmäen lukio, 1983-1985.

# **Certifications**

- AWS Architect Associate 2022. AWS Practitioner 2020.
- Foundation Certificate for Security, CISSP, 2022
- Level C Certified Project Management Professional, IPMA (International Project Management Association), 2022-2023.
- Microsoft Azure Academy, Microsoft Academy, Saranen. 2017-2018.
- Microsoft BizSpark 2015-2017. Building with Xamarin.

## **Risto Anton's Skills**

Competence Area	Experience	Last Used in Project / Program
Leadership & Management	15	2022
Project, productivity and collaboration management	15	2022 my primary tasks:
		<ul> <li>budget tracking skills</li> </ul>
Communication and teamwork	15	2022
Business development / innovation management	15	2022
Process development (eg. Lean)	10	2022
Agile organization / SAFe / kokonaisketterä.fi	10	2022
Design thinking and Service Design	5	2022
Continuous Delivery Software development	(years)	
C Application Development with traditional C / C++ languages // using Microsoft Visual Studio 2022 64-bit // with CMake 3.23.2 // and GCC 7.3.0 // on Windows 11.0.0 // with Visual Studio Code 1.69.0	15	2022 my primary tasks:  Coding .NET  Debugging Code Building Testing functionality Continuous delivery
Technical architecture or solution architecture design	10	2022
.NET 6 Multi-platform App development UI with a cross-platform framework for creating mobile and desktop apps with <b>C# 10 and XAML</b> .  with .NET MAUI developing native apps that run on Android, iOS, iPadOS, macOS, Tizen, Windows from a single shared codebase on GitHub.  https://github.com/dotnet/maui	7	https://github.com/bitfighter/bitfighter  Visual Studio 2022 Community  Ubuntu WSL  Docker
Database design ORM architecture	7	Design a testing strategy Create detailed designs for a solution
Build and version management on GitHub and Microsoft DevOps	7	2022
Configuration management IaC Terraform cloud	7	2022
Agile cicd for github actions -> Azure	7	2022
API Design / gateway management	7	2022
Cloud CI/CD Container fleet		Docker Desktop • CI/CD
AWS	7	<ul> <li>Compute: WordPress laaS Bitnami with Virtual Machines Debian Linux managing machines.</li> <li>PaaS managed machines.</li> <li>Azure App Services, provisioning pre-built SaaS images</li> <li>Storage, Messaging, Data, Networking</li> <li>Serverless with Azure Functions</li> </ul>

Microsoft Azure Developer	7	and Azure Logic Apps Containers Docker / k8s Registry Production Kubernetes Services Azure Pipelines CI/CD Compute: Azure laaS with Virtual Machines Linux/Windows Docker managing machines. PaaS managed machines. Running on Azure App Service, provisioning pre-built SaaS images and websites (web app architecture / API app) Storage, Messaging, Data, Networking Serverless with Azure Functions and Azure Logic Apps Container Docker images on k8s Azure Kubernetes Service Azure Pipelines CI/CD
Google Cloud	7	2022
Test automation Snyk Developer Security GitHub Copilot	3	2022
Testing and Debugging on Visual Studio 2022 / Code	7	2022
Performance testing	5	2022
Security testing Cybersecurity	5	2022
IT Infra		
IT Operations management Prometheus	7	2022
Data Science	5	2022
Ict security, continuous delivery Terraform	15	2022
Databases DynamoDB, Aurora, MariaDb	15	2022
Technical Skills		
HTML / CSS / XAML	15	2022
TypeScript	7	2022
JavaScript	15	2022
Angular.js / other .js framework	7	2022
Node.js Google Flutter	7	2022
C, C++, C#	7	2022
Golang	1	2022
.NET SDK	7	2022
AWS Toolkit, AWS CDK / CloudFormation / YAML / JSON	7	2022
Google Workspace Admin / GCE	10	2022
Python scripting / Jyputer	7	2022
React hooks	10	2022
Modeling / Business Model Development	15	2022
Product platforms		
Apache Spark 3.x / many	2	2022
IBM products Watson (Business Partner)	2	2022
IBM Cloud Paks	4	2022
Amazon Web Services (Consulting Partner)	4	2022
IBM DB2	2	2022
Postgres	2	2022
MySQL	10	2022
MS SQL Server	4	2022
MS Sharepoint Server	10	2022
MS Exchange Server / Office 365 Admin	7	2022
Ms Azure Architect		
	7	2022
MS DevOps	7 4	2022 2022
MS DevOps MS Hyper V		

Version management tools		
Git/ GitHub	7	2022
GitLab Community edition	5	2022
Atlassian JIRA	5	2022
Atlassian Confluence	5	2022
	5	2022
Mobile platforms Apple iOS	10	2022
		2022
Google Android	15	2022
OS platforms		
Apple OS X	6	2022
Linux Server / AMIs	15	2022
Windows Server /AMIs	15	2022
Testing tools		
DevSecOps	4	2022
Microsoft DevOps	5	2022
Sonarqube	0,2	
JMeter	0,2	
Jenkins	0,2	2020
Software products		
SAP	6	2022
MSOffice 365 Power Apps	6	2022
Container technologies		
Docker	6	2022
Kubernetes Management Platforms: Tanzu, Rancher	4	2022
API platforms		
Azure API gateway	6	2022
AWS API gateway	6	2022
IBM API gateway	6	2022
Google API gateway	6	2022
Cloud services		
Terraform cloud	4	2022
MS Azure Solutions Architect	6	2022
MS Office 365 Admin	7	2022
Google Workspace Admin	15	2022
Amazon Web Services (AWS) Architect Associate	6	2022
Business Sector Knowledge		
busiless sector knowledge	Experience in years	Last Used in Project / Program
Insurance		
Finance	4	2022
Retail	12	
Healthcare	4	
Government	6	
Telecom	4	
Media	12	
Energy	4	
Building Construction	1	
Process Knowledge		
	10+ years of	
Process Knowledge	company	
Process Knowledge	company finance	
Process Knowledge	company finance process	
Process Knowledge Finance	company finance process experience	
Process Knowledge	company finance process experience  10+ years of	
Process Knowledge Finance	company finance process experience	

IT Security and Administration	15+ years of IT	
,	Administration	
	process	
	experience	
Software Engineering	15+ years of	
	experience	
Sales	10+ years of	
	sales process	
	experience	
	CRM,	
	Salesforce	
Marketing	10+ years of	
	marketing	
	process	
	experience	
	Google	
Teamwork	15+ Team	
	leader and	
	member in	
	various	
	businesses and	
	industries	

**Project experience**Lifetime Digital Workspace for Intelligent Industries is an award winning project approved by the European Commission found here.

Project name: Lifetime Digital Workspace for Intelligent Industries Customer: Lifetime Group Certified Partners Consortium Time involved: 05/2018 - present	Description of project: What is the goal of the project Montreux (version 4)? What has been achieved so far? What is the desired outcome? Platform: AWS, Microsoft Azure AD, Linux AMIs Backend Services: DynamoDB, S3 datalake, see specs A. Frontend Services: Android, iOS, Metaverse AWS Services: See Appendix A.
	Own role(s): Project Manager, Cloud Solutions Architect, Developer Responsibilities:
	solution architecture for development, testing, production.
	database design, data lakehouse design
	UI design, mobile application, VR/AR
	design and implementation of DevOps and its Security
	continuous integration and deployment
Project name: CIMS Customer: EBAN Time involved:	Description of project: CIMS Platform: Microsoft Azure Software: HTML5, C# MS SQL Server, IIS Own role: Project Manager Responsibilities:
08/2015 -	managing project team of 5 specialists
	requirements specifications
	test planning, testing

# **Career history**

Updated June 12th, 2022

Lifetime Consulting	Job Title: Agile Project Manager
04/2018 - present	Main responsibilities:
	Project Planning, Project Costs, Project Resourcing.
	Project Portfolio
	Sprint Audit
	with agile, kanban, GitHub Actions, JIRA
	backlog owner
	Budgeting, Reporting
<b>Lifetime Studios</b> 04/2018 – present	Job Title: Cloud Developer Main responsibilities:
	Writing error-free code, Sprints work
	design and implementation of client solutions
	administering all testing and environments blue/green
	<ul> <li>testing DevSecOps tooling the client solution/ software</li> </ul>
Lifetime Studios	Job Title: Cloud Architect Main responsibilities:
	Writing error-free IaC code for Solutions
	Security of AWS Services
	Architectural design and implementation of client solutions
	administration of all testing and environments blue/green
	Strategy and Roadmap of DevSecOps, AMIs, Subscriptions
	tooling the client solution/ software.  AWS Control Tower Management for Accounts
	The control randyament to recounts
	Account Manager for client accounts.
	Containerization
	Team Leader for Projects.
<b>Lifetime Oy</b> 04/2018 –	Job Title: CEO Main responsibilities:
07/2010	- client consulting, contracting, sales.
	Administering site content for multiple customer services.
	,
	- Coding
	Managing Cloud environments and services.
	Security

Language skills
Finnish
English Native speaker

Fluent in project work and remote environments

Swedish Good Tjänstemans Språkprov

German **Basics** C#, Go, Node.JS, python, Fluent

GitOps

# **Smart Factory YAMK in Metropolia**

# **Curriculum Vitae**

7(9)

Updated June 12<sup>th</sup>, 2022

Year	Course	Grade	Training provider
2022	Älykkäät teolliset ratkaisut	4 out of 5	Metropolia YAMK tutkinto
2022	Tutkimusmenetelmät ja valmiudet	4 out of 5	Metropolia YAMK
09/2022	Projektien johtaminen		Metropolia YAMK
10/2022	Sovellettu seminaari I	Reunalaskennan valmiudet ja menetelmät	Metropolia YAMK
10/2022-04/202 3	Sovellettu seminaari II	Kyberturvallisuuden valmiudet ja menetelmät	Metropolia YAMK
04/2023-12/23	Insinöörityö		Metropolia YAMK
2022	CISSP Certified Information Security Professional	8 ECTS	Metropolia YAMK
2022	AWS Architect Certification		Amazon Web Services
2022	Certified Project Manager		IPMA

Updated June 12th, 2022

# My AI Voice Interview (Answers updated)

# What are you looking for in your next job?

As a Data Architect I want to analyze data sources and analyze data to find great solutions to the customer issues raised that they are facing in their business. To show customers data in appealing form is important, whether we use Tableau, Office 365, or other client tools.

As a Cloud Architect the building of new services for customer needs is important. Securing business continuity Identity Access Management, Monitoring, Containerization, SaaSes. Then there is security, Disaster Recovery Planning (DR), for example Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery with Amazon S3.

As Cloud Developer Building solid DevOps pipelines and teams associated with the right tooling and effective builds that follow secure policies like Snyk tooling, Git, Among others. IaC Scripts. I may lead a team or be a team member.

# Tell me about a time you had to deliver on multiple competing priorities. What did you do, and what were the results?

When there are multiple competing priorities, first, me and my team must prioritize and sort out which top three solutions and answers we need to solve urgently for the client.

and then I want to make a critical road map for those following priorities for the company to prioritize project portfolio and to meet the goals that our customer has set for us.

# You're putting together a presentation for a client using several data visualizations. What steps would you take in your final review of the presentation to make sure the information is clearly communicated?

In the presentation my team would state the problem first, then we would state the solution if available. Third, we would pinpoint the steps needed from the customer and from our side to reach a Go/No Go decision to deliver the solution to the customer problem.

# **Curriculum Vitae**

9(9)

Updated June 12<sup>th</sup>, 2022

# How can a subquery help aggregate data?

Subqueries are not generally allowed in aggregate functions. Instead, move the aggregate inside the subquery in SQL.

# When do you try to push through and solve a problem on your own, and when do you involve others on your team?

I evaluate our team members. under capabilities along with my own capabilities the see which combination gives the best answer to solving the problem.